Christopher J. Welborn

191 Maple Rd. Jasper, AL · (205) 275-9372

<u>cjwelborn@live.com</u>

<u>github.com/cjwelborn</u>

<u>github.com/welbornprod</u>

Computer-Aided Cabinet Design

OBJECTIVE:

To obtain a position where I can use my skills to create beautiful, and useful things, while supporting my family.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS:

I have been exploring computers and software-development since 1992, building/repairing houses since 2000, and designing/installing cabinets since 2005. I have worked to increase my skill level every day to create better, longer-lasting, results.

I have used insurance software (Xactimate/SimSol) to create digital estimates for remodels and whole-house rebuilds/repairs with detailed line items.

I have used cabinet design software (Mozaik, VCarve), CNC controller software (WinCNC), and programmable-saw software (TigerStop) to create parts, signs, cabinets (frames and boxes), etc.

I have written my own software (<u>TigerTamer</u>, <u>WinCNC-History</u>) to make these things easier, faster, and better.

I have worked in all areas of residential construction, and specialize in detailed trim or cabinet work.

SKILLS SUMMARY:

- Computers
 - Windows
 - Linux
 - Software Development
 - C, Python, JavaScript, VBA, BASH, HTML, CSS/SASS (and others)
 - Version Control Software (Git)
- Cabinets
 - Design Software (Mozaik, VCarve)
 - CNC Part Fabrication (WinCNC, GCode)
 - Building, Installing
- Construction (Residential)
 - Framing, Drywall, Flooring, Electrical, Plumbing, Roofing

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Millwork Supply Inc., Jasper, AL (10/2019 – Today)

Manager / Cabinet Draftsman / Purchase Agent

Reference: Brian Keeton (Former Manager) 205-300-0334

Cabinet design using Mozaik, Cut-list/plan generation for all departments, Final measurements/confirmations, Customer info documentation, Material/Supply ordering.

Software-related Projects:

I used Excel, VBA, and Python code to speed up the cut-list generation procedure, store and recall customer/job information, track inventory, and generate purchase orders. I drastically reduced the amount of inefficient/duplicated work, and used my tools to provide consistent information with consistent formatting.

B & M Cabinets, Jasper, AL (2/2014 – 10/2019)

Designer / Fabricator / Installer

Reference: Tim Davidson (Foreman) 205-544-5973

Cabinet design using Mozaik, fabrication using a ShopSabre 408 CNC, controlled with WinCNC, face-frame building with parts created on a TigerStop (programmable saw stop), cabinet assembly, and in-home installation (all trim-work included).

Software-related Projects:

I wrote several GCode programs to streamline day-to-day operations. I also wrote a cut-list parser for TigerStop (programmable saw stop) to correct output coming from Mozaik cut-lists, being fed into the TigerStop. I configured, networked, and maintained three PCs driving our cabinet design and fabrication.

Self-Employed Subcontractor, Jasper, AL (2005 – 2014)

Home Concepts LLC, Jasper, AL (2/2012 – 7/2014)

Estimator / Laborer / Installer / Problem Solver

Reference: Mike Dill (Owner) 205-522-0855

General construction, computerized estimates, granite installation, cabinet installation, and various other repairs/remodels.

Software-related Projects:

Created a "business-card" website built with Python/Django, JavaScript, and HTML/CSS. It included a web application that allowed clients to contact us for support/price-queries.

The application filtered spam/noise, and forwarded requests to managers for review via e-mail. Queries were listed in the administrative front-end, and could be edited by managers.

Jeris Crump Construction LLC, Jasper, AL (2/2005 – 4/2009) **Estimator / Laborer / Team Leader / Problem Solver**

General construction, computerized estimates using industry standard software (Simsol & Xactimate), cabinet design/installation, team leading, billing, and various other construction related duties.

Software-related Projects:

Created and used a custom expense tracking application built with Visual Basic .Net.

Tracked labor costs, receipts, and time, per job. Data was easily queried and formatted thanks to the application design.

EDUCATION:

Bucks County Community College Newtown, PA United States 1/2004

1 Semester

Credits Earned: 10

Major: Computer Science

Bevill State Community College Jasper, AL United States 11/1998

2 Semesters

Credits Earned: 32

Major: Computer Science

Jericho Way (Private School) Cordova, AL United States 1997

Early High School Graduation College ACT Exam Passed